adelement.com 2017-12-21

# Behavioral Targeting Privacy Policy | AdElement

Welcome to the web site of AdElement Media Solutions Pvt. Ltd. We provide online advertising solution and services to our clients. This privacy policy describes collection of information from users of our Web site at http://www.adelement.com (the " **Site** ") and the various products, solutions and services we provide to our clients (the " **Services** "). By using our Site or our Services, you consent to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

From time to time we may make changes to this policy and publish the same on our website with the date of last update. These changes will supersede any prior changes. Your continued use of our site, product or services after such changes have been published is subject to the updated policy. We encourage you to periodically review our policy to stay informed about how we collect, use and disclose personal information.

#### Personally Identifiable information

Personally Identifiable information as used in this policy, is information that specifically identifies a person, such as a person's name, address, telephone number, mobile number or e-mail address. Personally Identifiable information also includes information about a person's activities, such as information about his or her activity on our Site or our Services, and demographic information, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area, and preferences, when any of this information is linked to personal information that identifies that person.

#### Aggregate information

Aggregate information is information that we collect about a group or category of products, services, or users that is not personally identifiable or from which individual identities are removed.

#### Cookies

A cookie, also known as a web cookie, browser cookie, and HTTP cookie, is a piece of text stored on a user's computer by their web browser. A cookie can be used for authentication, storing site preferences, shopping cart contents, the identifier for a server-based session, or anything else that can be accomplished through storing text data.

#### Personally Identifiable information

We collect Personally Identifiable Information (PII) on www.adelement.com when you voluntarily provide that information to us, for example when you complete an online form, register, access your account, enter billing preferences or email us PII information. This information is used to 

  * Provide you services, information or contact you to respond to your inquiry
  * Improve, operate and maintain our site, services, systems and resources
  * Bill for our services, collect amounts owed to us
  * Tailor your user experience, maintain a record of dealings with you, administrative purposes and prevent fraudulent use of our site and services

#### Aggregate information

We collect aggregate or non-PII information that may include your IP address, pages viewed, time spent, events triggered, browser used, computer's operating system, internet service provider (ISP), referring URL, time and date of your visit, etc. This information is collected passively using standard web server logs, cookies and web beacons (also know as 1x1 pixels). This information is used to improve, operate and maintain our site, services, systems and resources. We may use and disclose aggregate information, and other non-personally identifiable information, for various purposes.

#### Cookies

We use cookies and web beacons to collect aggregate non-PII data that is used to improve, operate and maintain our site, services, system and resources.

#### Links & third party websites

Our site contains links to third party websites or services that we do not own or operate. Our privacy policy does not apply to any of these third party website or services and we cannot be responsible for their privacy practices.

#### Deleting your Personally Identifiable Information

If you would like us to delete any PII that you have provided us please email us a request to remove your information at security@adelement.com and we will process your request within a reasonable period of time.

#### Overview of our Services

We provide online advertising services to our clients. When you visit websites that our clients or we have purchased advertisements on, and/or our clients or partners place our web beacons on their websites that you visit, we collect non-PII information about that visit.

#### Personally Identifiable information

We do not collect any Personally Identifiable Information (PII) through our Services.

#### Aggregate information

We collect aggregate or non-PII information that includes, but is not limited to your IP address, pages viewed, time spent, events triggered (e.g. clicks), browser used, computer's operating system, internet service provider (ISP), referring URL, time and date of your visit. This information is completely anonymous and used to improve the relevance of advertisements shown to you.

#### Cookies

We use cookies and web beacons on our partner and our client websites to collect aggregate non-PII data including but not limited to interests, behaviors, type of activity, pages visited, date/time of visit, ip address, browser, ISP. This information is used make advertisements more relevant to you and or measure success of our or our clients advertising campaigns.

#### Opting Out of Behavioral Advertising (Web Browsers)

If you'd like to opt out from AdElement collecting your Non-PII in connection with serving behavioral ads on our network of web sites, please [click here](http://www.adelement.com/company/optout/?type=optout). When you opt out, an opt out cookie is placed on your computer. This cookie tells us not to collect your Non-PII to tailor online advertisement campaigns. Please note that if you change your computer, change your Internet browser (e.g. from Chrome to Firefox), or delete all your cookies, you will need to renew your opt out. You can check your [opt out status here](http://www.adelement.com/company/optout).

#### Opting Out of Behavioral Advertising (Mobile Applications)

If you would like to opt-out from AdElement collecting your Non-PII in connection with serving behavioral ads on our network of mobile applications you will have to be browsing inside a mobile application environment. When you are served a behaviorally targeted ad from us you can opt-out by clicking on the opt out button accesible from ad choices icon integrated in all our behaviorally targeted ads. By doing this we are able to capture the advertising device identifier for your mobile device, store it on our servers and then stop showing your advertising device identifier the behaviorally targeted ads. Please note if you reset your advertising device identifier you will have to renew your opt out status.

This procedure will only block ads that are displayed by AdElement. If you want to block these type of ads from other advertising providers please follow instructions below:

**Android Users (version 2.3 and above)**  
To opt out of interest-based or behaviorally advertising for your Android Device, follow the instructions provided by Google here to "opt out of interest-based advertising" [ Google Play Help](https://support.google.com/googleplay/answer/3405269). If you do not have the Google Play Services installed on your device, you wonâ€™t be shown ads from AdElement. Please note that this is a device setting and will disable interest-based ads from all providers, not just AdElement

 **iOS users (version 6 and above)**  
To opt out of interest-based or behaviorally advertising for your iOS Device, follow the instructions provided by Apple here to "Turn on Limit Ad Tracking": [Apple Support Center](https://support.apple.com/en-in/HT202074).Please note that this is a device setting and will disable interest-based ads from all providers, not just AdElement

#### Third Party Websites

Our advertisements/ web beacons or our clients advertisements / web beacons maybe seen on third party websites or services that we do not own or operate. Our privacy policy does not apply to any of these third party website or services and we cannot be responsible for their privacy practices.

* * *

## Information relating to Children

Our products and services are designed for those over 13 years of age or older. We do not knowingly collect any Personally Identifiable Information from anyone under the age of 13.

* * *

## Disclosure of Information to Third Parties

We may disclose personally identifiable information about our users to third party service providers (e.g. data storage and processing providers) that assist us in our work. We limit the personal information we provide to these service providers that is necessary for them to perform their work for us. We may also disclose PII information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are required by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action against suspected or actual prohibited activities.

* * *

## Storage of Information

PII information we collect through our Site is stored for a reasonable time record keeping purposes and to improve our site and services. This information is deleted in normal course of business or as space is required. Non-PII information we collect through our Service maybe stored for up to 24 months, after which it is only stored in aggregate format.

* * *

_Last Updated: 12 Feb 2016_
